What is the best strategy for pricing
when it comes to your course or your
membership or your subscription or your
high ticket program? And what do
different price points say about your
product? How people trust you? Well, in
today's video, I want to talk about
pricing for coaches, mentors, service
providers. One of the biggest pieces of
advice I see that's out there is, okay,
look what everybody else is charging and
then charge something similar. And
unfortunately, this is not really very
good advice. The reason why is because
your competitors that are out there,
they might not know anything about
pricing. And the people that you're
looking at as far as how they price
things probably are undercutting
themselves in a way where if you did
what they did, you wouldn't make as much
money. What I like to look at is this.
What are the leaders in my industry
charging? What are the people who are
leading the way doing in their business?
And I'll tell you, in the coaching
business, there is a wide range of fees.
On the high end, it's $30,000.
In the consulting space, that can go all
the way up to multiple seven figures. In
fact, by the way, that's a lot of people
don't realize that consulting can make
you seven figures. Coaching can make you
multiple six figures per client per
year. And courses, well, courses usually
sell for anywhere between 500 to
upwards. I've seen some courses sell for
$5,000. Okay? So, how do you decide how
to price things? Well, the first thing
I'm going to say is this. Don't be the
cheapest option. The reason why you
don't want to be the cheapest option is
because being the cheapest option means
that you're not going to get the right
people engaging with you. you're not
going to have the right people on board
with you when you work with them. Here's
the reason why. When you're the cheapest
option, you're finding what is called
value seekers. And you might be watching
this video right now saying, "Well, I'm
a value seeker. What does that mean? I'm
the wrong person." You might be for a
specific product. Because here's what
I'm talking about is you want to find
people that truly are willing to part
the Red Sea, pay anything to solve the
problem that you will. I'm going to give
you an example. My air conditioning went
out at my house the other day.
I was willing to pay whatever the
marketplace asked me to pay, which was
right around $10,000 for my house to
have air conditioning back in my house.
I wasn't going to sit there without AC
for six months and say, "Well, we'll
price it out. We'll figure out the best
deal. I'm going to go shop around." No.
My family needed air conditioning in my
house that day. And they figured out a
deal to make me be able to do that. I
was able to to get a really good deal on
on how to be able to pay for that. And
so, it's what's awesome is is like
that's what you want to do. You want to
make it very easy for the right prospect
who has a need and has a problem. You
might be saying, "Well, Jeremiah, isn't
that exploiting people's problems?"
I guess in a sense, you could see it as
that. And I would say that one of the
things is is that every business does
that. Restaurants exploit the fact that
you're hungry. Okay? Like car
dealerships exploit the fact that you
need transportation. So, every business
at its core takes a need and then fills
it.
I want you to think about when you go
car shopping. Have you ever gone car
shopping, but you're not ready to buy,
right? You ever noticed the
salesperson's not really, they don't
want to give you a lot of attention
because you're not a buyer. And you
might find that to be disrespectful and
all that. You might say, "I want I want
to be treated red carpet, all that."
Listen, I understand. I get it. I get
where you're coming from. I get what
your desire is. I get what you want. But
can I tell you this? As a business
owner,
you need to do what is best for your
cash flow in your business, which is
focusing your energy and efforts on who
is going to pay me money today to solve
a problem
to get a result. When I work with my
clients, I help them to get more
clients. I show them exactly what steps
to take to grow their email list. I show
them exactly what to do step by step to
be able to get results better than the
other coaches that are out there. I show
them how to stop losing money with their
Facebook ads and their Instagram ads.
And I show them exactly what to say and
how to say it to attract the right
clients to them and get people to pay.
And so, listen, if you're listening to
me right now, again,
you're here because you want to learn
how to get people to pay. So, one of the
keys is with pricing is you want to
price it in a way
where people who are serious are going
to buy from you. You don't just want
anybody and the economics don't work out
by being the cheapest option. The reason
why is because if you are simply merely
the cheapest option on the market,
there's not enough economics there for
you to have a real business. You're not
going to be able to pay for advertising.
You're not going to be able to keep the
lights on. You're not going to be able
to pay for staff as as you grow. And by
the way, when I talk about staff, I'm
saying like you can hire people in the
Philippines for $5 an hour that can work
full-time with you. And that's a truly
great wage for them. but they can help
and assist you to grow your business so
that you're not the one doing
everything. And that's important to do.
In my business, I have multiple people
that work with me. They work with me.
They come alongside me and I work with
them to build my business. As a business
owner, it's important for you to
position yourself for maximum
profitability and attracting the right
clients to you. So, when it comes to
pricing, it is a boundary.
You can't be all to everybody that's out
there. And if you're underpriced, you're
literally missing out on a ton of money
that's out there. You might say, "Yeah,
but Jeremiah, if I charged more, I'd
have less people."
You would make more money, though. Let
me explain. Less people paying you more
money equals more money.
If I have a hundred people paying me 10
bucks,
50 people paying me $30
is going to make me more money. I'm
going to make $1,000 off of a hundred
people paying me $10.
Whereas, if I have 50 people paying me
30, that's $1,500.
So, that's higher profitability. And
those 50 people are more serious about
the need and the desire. And there's an
economic curve here as how this happens
with pricing. There is a price point
where people won't buy and there's a few
things to decide with that. If people
won't buy from you, there's two things
that are at play here. Usually, it's
actually not that you price too much,
the offer just is not attractive enough
to them because again, the right offer
to the right person that solves the
right problem, people will say yes to
and they will pay you for it. And so if
your offer is not solving a big enough
problem for people, you need to
redevelop your offer so that it solves a
big enough problem so that they will pay
you. And really, this is where we can't
let our ego get in place while I do this
or I do that or this is what I do all
the time and I I'm afraid to change my
offer or adjust it or do that because I
don't want to offend people or things
like my friends,
take your emotions out of this side of
things when it comes to pricing. Pricing
is not an emotional equation at all. It
is very much logical. And that's one of
the reasons why a lot of coaches,
mentors, and service providers, they
attach their identity to their pricing.
Now, I've seen it both ways. They
undercut themselves because they really
have this whole like
superhero messiah mantle type of a
thing. I want to be all things to
everybody and I want to help so many
people. and then they're losing
money because they're not charging
enough or they charge so much and nobody
is going to pay them. And so if like
nobody is going to pay you, what you're
looking for is you want to look for a
closing rate of right around like 30%
of the people that you get to make an
offer to. And I'm talking ones who go
all the way through your offer. Like if
I get leads on my email list, I'm not
talking about 30% of my leads. That's
like 3% of the leads are going to sign
up. But out of the leads that sign up,
how many of them go through the whole
presentation?
Out of those who go through the whole
presentation,
a good 30% are going to become a client.
And that's effective. And that's how you
know your offer stack is effective.
If you're going to price something
cheap, like I'm going to be launching a
class here real soon all about Instagram
ads. It's an Instagram ads playbook, and
I'm going to charge
uh $4.95 for it.4
$4.95, really cheap. I'm not making
money on that. It's going to merely pay
for my ad spend. But what it does is it
qualifies people better than a free
offer. If it's a free offer, I'm going
to have a lot of people who are not
serious. If I'm charging five bucks, I'm
going to have a lot of people who are
serious. And those who pay that are
going to be more willing to become my
client. Okay? So, when it comes to like
pricing tiers, here's how we price
things out. In my low ticket offers, I
usually do like five to seven dollars.
And these are merely just attraction
offers to attract new leads, new people
into my ecosystem, into my space who can
become a potential client. From there, I
have my Wealthy Coach Academy program.
Right now, we charge $197 a month for
it. I have a 14-day free trial. At the
end of the trial, I also give people
$120 off their first month. So, I'm
giving a really good deal. I mean,
that's a really good deal. It really is.
That's unheard of in this industry for
the value that we offer. We have tons of
courses. You get coaching with me. I
help you build your landing pages and
the language of your ads and exactly
what to say, how to say it, how to put
it all together, how to get more
clients, exactly what to do, all the
nuances of that in there for that. The
value is incredible. And then above
that, I have my $900 a month VIP
program. Above that, I have my $8,000 a
month consulting offer. $8,000 a month.
Well, who's paying that? Well, a
business owner who's already making a
million, paying $8,000 a month to have
me consult them so they can go to 10
million is very affordable. Okay? And I
and I have multiple clients that pay at
each of these levels. And this is what
my business is, is I want to ascend the
$495 person up to the $8,000 level.
Maybe you're watching this right now.
I'd love to work with you at whatever
level works best for you. You know, we
have these new courses coming out. You
can find some of our latest courses. We
still have a couple free ones that are
in the in the description below.
The goal is to ascend people up the
ladder and you price out each tier
depending on what the different price
points are. So like low tier, I would do
under 50 bucks. Your low ticket
attraction offer. This is like a lead
magnet, but you charge money for it.
It's like an opt-in offer where people
give you their email address. But the
problem is that now a lot of people, you
don't want freebie seekers. So, if you
charge just a little bit of money, even
if it's five bucks, cuz that's what I
like to do. Five bucks goes a long way
because then my next offer after that is
free 14-day trial, which is just a
no-brainer for those people. They
already spent five bucks, might as well
do something for free. and and if they
like it, the only risk to that is
another $77 after that. Okay? And so
from there, like that is exactly
what we do in our business. That's
exactly what I've done for the longest
time to be able to get clients, to be
able to have the economics work out to
where we're making the kind of money
that we know we need to make in our
business.
You need to price things out so that you
are profitable and so that you're
attracting the right people and so that
you're repelling the wrong ones, the
ones that are not a good fit for working
with you. And that's a really good thing
to do. That's a really great thing to do
in fact. And so what I would recommend
if you're a business owner, if you're a
coach, if you're a mentor, if you're
somebody who is building a business and
you're trying to figure out, okay,
what's the right way to do all this? How
can I make sure that I'm not wasting my
time, that I'm not undervaluing myself?
One of the best things you can do is get
into an environment like my Wealthy
Coach Academy program. We can look at
your offer. We can look at exactly what
you're doing to help you know how to
price things. You can also leave a
comment below this video and I can just
leave a quick little comment back to you
on that. That's something a free service
that I offer people is being able to
comment back on the videos that I
create. And so that's something that I
would like to do, would like to help you
with. If you're a coach, if you're a
mentor, if you're a service provider,
you owe it to yourself to get paid, to
get paid significantly for what you do,
to not undercut yourself for the type of
value that you offer people. The type of
value that you offer people is
tremendous.
It's worth it to charge what you're
worth. Know your worth. See yourself
that as if you are solving a problem for
somebody, a real true valid actual
problem that you are solving for
somebody, they will pay you in exchange
for solving that problem and for
alleviating the pain that they are
experiencing. You are a pain killer.
You're killing and alleviating the pain
that they are experiencing by having
this problem. And if you do that, if you
if you come to the table in your
business and you're willing to lay aside
your fears, your worries, your
hesitations, the resistance that you
have to this, and you say, you know
what?
I'm going to do what Jeremiah says. I'm
going to follow him. He's been doing
this a long time. I've I've been in this
industry for 22 almost 23 years, and I
know exactly what it takes to get
results in a business like this. as a
business owner like you, what to do to
be able to get the kind of results that
you want. And so, if you follow what I'm
saying in this video for pricing, you
could make a ton of money. The different
tiers you have, the low ticket tier,
right?
Uh, under $47. The next tier up if it's
a course
500 to
$5,000.
Uh, a high ticket would be 6,000 to
6,000 to
$19,000. And then above that, you might
go to 30,000 upwards to 60 or 70,000
from there. In your offers, you're like,
what would I what would I offer people
that they would pay that much money for?
Well, if you solve a big enough problem,
people are willing to pay you that much
money. What I recommend a lot of coaches
do is this. I I recommend you have your
low ticket offer under 27 bucks. You
have a coaching program that's maybe 97
to 197 bucks a month. You can offer a
trial or discount on the initial ticket
to that.
And then from there,
offer some kind of like a $10,000 a year
with a monthly payment offer like I do.
900 bucks a month. Those price points
are really tested. They're dialed in and
they work. And then above that, find
something that you can do that that
might be over $100,000 a year. 100k a
year offer. That's what my $8,000 a
month offer is. Something that you can
make a h 100k a year from one client.
And usually, again, there's probably
going to be some kind of a service, some
kind of a white glove thing that you're
doing with that, but the right person
will pay it. They will. There's so much
money available out there, you don't
even realize it. Most people don't
realize how much money is available in
the world until they go out there and
they start selling and they realize,
"Okay, I can actually make a significant
income, a full-time income doing what I
love in my business by simply raising my
prices, by simply finding the right
people to work with." And that's what
you can do in your business. And I'd
love to help you do that inside of my
Wealthy Coach Academy program. Click one
of the links below, jump in, check it
out, try it out. We'll see you in there.
We'll talk soon. Have a good one.